When we left for Bastogne...
当我们向着巴斯通出发
...we were short of equipment, we didn't have enough ammunition...
我们缺少装备 弹药不足
...we didn't have enough warm clothes.
也没有足够的御寒衣物
But we had confidence...
可是我们相信
...that our higher military authorities would get to us whatever we needed.
我们的长官将会补给我们所需的物资
And there was a ridge with a tree line. We were dug in on that ridge.
那有座位于林线的山脊 我们在山脊上挖战壕
The Germans knew right where we were, and they really gave us a shellacking.
德军很清楚我们在那儿 对我们进行猛烈炮轰
Like in Bastogne, we were down to one round per man there for a while.
在巴斯通 我们曾经每人只剩一排子弹
The fog was in.
当地又起雾
They couldn't drop us or resupply us.
无法进行空投补给
Every time they tried to drop supplies in to us...
他们每次要对我们进行物资空投
...they missed us and dropped them to the Germans.
都会错过我们投给了德军
One of the guys got hit in the arm with a piece of shrapnel.
有个家伙手臂被炮弹碎片击中
Took his arm off above the elbow.
结果手肘以下全部炸断
And they were taking him out, he said, "Get my wristwatch off my arm."
他们要将手臂截肢 他只说 "把我的手表拿下来"
And then a medic came along, and I think he really saved my life...
然后一个医护兵来了 我想他真是救了我一命
...because he stuck a Syrette in a key position. Morphine.
因为他在我的关键部位打了一针吗啡
Even today, a real cold night...
即使是现在 当我们在寒夜上床睡觉时
...we go to bed and my wife will tell you that...
我太太会告诉你...
...first thing I'll say is, "I'm glad I'm not in Bastogne."
我讲的第一句话是："很庆幸我不是在巴斯通"
Duck, duck, duck!
蹲下 蹲下 蹲下!
Kommen Sie hier.
过来...快点!(德语)
Schnell!
快点!(德语)
Doc, bandage.
医生 绷带
Take him back to Regiment.
带他回团部
As you all know, General McAuliffe, Acting Division Commander.
你们都知道麦考利夫将军现在是代师长
Give it to me straight!
把战况老实跟我说
We've been taking ground in one position, General...
将军 我们占领了一个点
...losing it in another.
同时就又失去另一个点
And now it looks like a standoff. We're digging in on the edge of the forest.
现在看来形成僵局 我们正在森林边缘挖战壕
We're under sporadic artillery fire, General.
将军 我们遭遇到全面的炮火轰击
We're taking a lot of hits, and we have no aid station.
我们很多人受伤甚重却没有医疗站
We've run out of food, we have no winter clothes...
我们的粮食耗尽 没有冬装
...and we have little or no ammo.
仅有少量 甚至没有弹药
The line's spread so thin, the enemy wanders into our CP to use our slit trenches, sir.
战线分布太宽 敌人可以利用缝隙溜进我们指挥所
We just can't cover the line.
我们守不住整个战线
Good morning, Captain Nixon.
早安 尼克森上尉
You got anything to add for General McAuliffe?
你还有什么要跟麦考利夫将军报告的吗?
General, yes, sir.
将军 有的
General, I took a walk along the line about 0300 last night.
将军 凌晨3点我到战线走了一趟
Couldn't find the 501st on our right flank.
却找不到右翼的501团
I tied in with a squad from our 2nd Platoon.
我用我们第二排其中的一班去填补空缺
But, sir, we've got some considerable gaps in our perimeter.
可是长官 我们的防线空隙实在是太大了
I don't have enough people, sir. We're spread too damn thin.
我的人手不足 长官 我们分散得太广了
Hold the line, Colonel, close the gaps.
守住战线 上校 把缝隙填满
This goddamn fog won't lift any time soon...
这场雾短期内不会散去
...so you can forget about air cover.
所以你们也别指望空中支援
Your 1st Battalion just pulled out of Foy, Krauts on their tail.
你们的第一营刚从佛依撤退 德军一路追击他们
Tanks, artillery. Got no backup.
对方有坦克 炮兵 他们也没有后援
There's a lot of shit heading this way.
我们要遭遇的麻烦还真多
Can I scrounge a bandage from your aid kit, sir?
我可以从你医药箱里借条绷带吗 长官?
How are you fixed?
你现在情况如何?
No plasma, couple of bandages. Practically no morphine.
没有血浆 几条绷带 可以说是没有吗啡
I tried to find my way up to 3rd Battalion...
事实上 我曾试着去三营拿些补给
...looking for supplies, but lost my way.
可是 我迷路了
If you can't get over to 3rd, hook up with Doc Ryan.
你如果找不到三营的话 那就联络莱恩医生
He'll fix you up with what he has to spare.
他会尽可能的补给你
Thanks, Captain.
谢谢你 上尉
Eugene, get everything you can.
尤金 你能拿多少就拿多少
You're gonna need it.
会派上用场的
- Spina. - Doc. - What's happening?
- 史宾纳? - 医生 - 出什么事了?
- We're digging in right along the line. - Yeah?
- 我们在防线上挖战壕 - 是吗?
Yeah, this is it.
就这样
So, what'd you get?
你拿到些什么?
I got this.
我拿到这个
And I got myself a Kraut bandage.
我还拿到条德军绷带
What, this is it?
什么? 就这些?
Yeah, that's it, that's all you got.
对! 就这样 只有这些了
Jesus
老天
You know, 1st Battalion's pulled out of Foy.
第一营撤出佛依了
Heavy casualties.
死伤惨重
If they're pulling back, why are we sitting here?
既然他们撤退了 我们还坐在这里干嘛?
We need morphine, this is all I've got.
我们需要吗啡 我只剩这些
You got extra scissors?
你有多一把剪刀吗?
Just the one.
没有 只有这一支
- First Sergeant Lipton! - Sir.
- 李普军士长! - 长官
What's this?
这是什么?
- Two medics in one hole? - Yes, sir.
- 两个医护兵在一个坑里? - 没错
What's gonna happen to us if you take a hit?
要是你们被一炮打中! 我们要怎么办?
Sir?
长官?
First Sergeant, where's my foxhole?
军士长 我的散兵坑呢?
It's back here, sir.
就在后面 长官
Maybe you missed it.
或许您刚错过了
I'll walk you back, sir. You're a bit close to the line here.
我带您回去 长官 你靠前线稍微近了点
Goddamn it.
可恶
Sergeant Guarnere, did you keep your morphine from Holland?
葛奈瑞中士! 你从荷兰带来的吗啡还有吗?
No.
不在了
Doc, I've gotta talk to you.
医生 我有话跟你说
How's that leg?
你腿怎么啦?
To hell with the leg, I'm pissing needles.
去他的腿 我小便会痛!
Later.
待会儿再说...
Shit!
可恶!
You seen them?
有没有看到德军?
No. But they're out there.
没有! 可他们就在那里
Depend on it.
相信我
Cup of joe, Doc?
来杯咖啡吗 医生?
Gordon, I need scissors.
戈登 我需要剪刀
You got scissors, sharp scissors?
你有剪刀吗? 很利的剪刀
Scissors?
剪刀?
Well, let's see, I'll have to check the sewing room.
让我看看 我得去缝纫室找找
Might be upstairs in the study.
或许在楼上书房里
That skinny drawer in the middle of the desk.
书桌中间细长老旧的抽屉里
All right, what about an extra Syrette in your aid kit?
好吧! 你有没有多余的止痛药?
Hide your morphine, guys.
大伙儿把吗啡藏好
- Muck, you all right? - I'm good!
- 马克 你还好吧? - 我没事
Muck, Malarkey, take cover! We're okay!
马克 马拉其 找掩体
Take a look at this shit! They've peppered my helmet!
你们看看? 他们把我的头盔弄的全是灰
Doc, morphine.
医生 吗啡
Here, take it! Where's Penkala?
拿去! 潘卡拉到哪儿去了?
Christ knows.
天知道
Medic!
医护兵~
Doc!
医生!
- Medic! - You guys hit?
- 医护兵! - 你们受伤了吗?
Doc, what are you doing? Are you crazy?
医生 你在干什么? 你疯啦?
What are you looking at him for? Watch the goddamn line.
你盯着他看干什么? 看好你的战线
- You got a Syrette? - No.
- 你有止痛针吗? - 没有
Medic!
医护兵!
Doc!
医生!
Penkala!
潘卡拉
Doc! It's the artery, I can feel it!
医生!是动脉 我感觉得到
- Penkala, let go... - It's the goddamn artery!
- 潘卡拉 放松 - 是动脉!
Penkala, loosen your fingers, goddamn it!
潘卡拉 松开你的手指 可恶 快放松!
- I'll bleed to death. - Relax your arm, Penky!
- 我会失血过多而死! - 松开手! 快点!
- It's not the artery. - I ain't going back, Doc.
- 不是动脉! - 我不要回去了 医生
- What? - I ain't going nowhere, not in this shit.
- 什么? - 在这种情况下我哪儿都不去
You don't wanna go, and you yell medic?
你不想出去还喊医务兵?
I don't need to go back to no aid station.
我不想去没有医疗站的地方
You're in luck, Penkala, because we don't got no aid station.
算你运气好 潘卡拉 我们这儿也没有医疗站
Penkala, I need scissors. You got scissors?
潘卡拉 剪刀 你有剪刀吗?
What the hell I need scissors for?
我带剪刀干什么?
Got your aid kit?
有带急救包吗?
Right, you don't need this, not yet.
好 你现在还不需要这个
I do.
我比较需要
- Who got hit? - Penkala.
- 谁受伤了? - 潘卡拉
All right, this is what I want you to do.
这样吧 我要你这么做
I want you to take someone and work your way to the 3rd Battalion.
我要你带个人想办法去三营
You know what we need: Bandages, plasma.
我们需要绷带 血浆
Whatever you can beg, you beg, all right?
你能讨什么都讨来 知道吗?
And get me some goddamn scissors. I can't get any.
还有给我拿剪刀来 我一把也没有
And you get yourself a hot meal, too.
你自己也弄个热餐吃
Go.
去吧!
You know, he told me he was a goddamn virgin.
他说他还是处男
Who?
谁?
The replacement in my foxhole, Julian.
在我散兵坑里的新兵朱利安
Yeah?
是吗?
Goddamn virgin. Just a kid.
还是处男 根本只是个小孩
The only virgin I know is the Virgin Mary.
我唯一知道的处子是"圣母玛利亚"
Hey, Babe, where the hell are we?
贝比! 我们到底在哪儿?
This way.
往这边走
I don't like it.
我不喜欢这样
Where the hell is 3rd Battalion?
三营到底在哪儿?
Shit!
糟糕
Come on.
快上来!
- Come on, come on, give me a hand. - Go, go!
- 快点 把手伸过来 - 快走!
- Come on, Spina, move! - I'm moving!
- 快点 史宾纳 快跑! - 我在跑
Get moving! Come on, go!
跑快点 快点 跑
Okay, we can spare a few bandages, but that's it.
我们可以分一点绷带给你 但只有这些了
No morphine.
没有吗啡
You'll have to go back to Bastogne for plasma.
你们得回巴斯通找血浆
It took us an hour to find you.
巴斯通? 我们花了一小时才找到你们
Doesn't your surgeon have plasma?
你们的外科大夫没有血浆吗?
We don't have one. No surgeon, no aid station, nothing.
我们没有外科大夫 我们没有外科大夫 也没有医疗站 什么都没有
Just me and my buddy.
只有我跟我的伙伴
Sorry, guys, but we just can't help you.
很抱歉 我们就是没有办法帮你们
Take cover!
找掩体!
Get your butts out of here! We're pulling back!
快离开这里 我们要撤退了!
Come on, let's go!
快点 我们走!
Move!
快走!
Should have shot Hinkle in the ass! And you would have shot him in the ass!
真该一枪打烂那德佬的屁股 然后德佬也回一枪 让他屁股开花!
God bless ya.
上帝保佑
Yo, these smell like my armpit.
这闻起来像是我的腋窝
At least your armpit's warm.
至少你的腋窝是温暖的
Do you want syrup with that?
那你要加糖浆吗?
Joe, be honest. What's in these things anyway?
乔 你老实说 这里面放的到底是什么东西?
- Nothing you won't eat, Malarkey. - I won't eat malarkey.
- 没有你不吃的 马拉其 - 我不吃马拉其
Maybe Hinkle would like your share?
也许德国佬会喜欢你那套
- Should've shot him when I could. - Running backwards?
- 我早该一枪毙了他 - 贝比 你会倒着跑吗?
Anybody seen Lieutenant Dike?
有人看到戴克中尉吗?
Try Battalion CP, sir.
问问看营指挥所 长官
Try Paris.
问问看巴黎
Try Hinkle.
问问看德国佬
"Hinkle, sweetie, I'm home."
亲爱的德国佬 我回家了
Eugene, Lieutenant Dike's got a full aid kit. Try him.
尤金 戴克中尉有个完整的急救包 找他试试看
Yeah, I'm sure he's not using his.
对 我相信他都还没有用到
Maybe Hinkle's got a Syrette for you.
也许德佬有止痛针给你
Eat your strudel. Hinkle-vinkle, eat the armpit?
吃你的馅饼 阿德仔 吃胳肢窝
Lieutenant Dike.
戴克中尉
Can you spare something from your aid kit? I'm short. I need Syrettes.
能分点急救包吗 长官? 我们很缺 需要止痛针
- What, morphine? - Yes, sir.
- 要吗啡吗? - 是的 长官
What happens if I get hit?
如果我中弹怎么办?
I'll be there, sir.
我会来救你的 长官!
- Syrettes in here, right? - Yes, it is.
- 止痛针在里面 对吧? - 是的
Here.
给你
I don't plan on getting hit.
我不准备中弹的
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
Heffron.
赫夫朗
Heffron, you okay?
赫夫朗 你还好吗?
Gene, what is with the Heffron bullshit?
尤金! 你叫我的姓干嘛?
You know my name. Why don't you use it?
你明知道我的名为何不用?
It's Edward, right?
你叫爱德华 对不对?
Edward? Are you serious? Only the goddamn nuns call me Edward.
爱德华? 你是认真的吗? 只有修女会叫我爱德华
I need to know if you kept your morphine from Holland.
听着 我要知道你还有没有从荷兰带来的吗啡?
No, you asked me already, remember?
你已经问过我了 还记得吗?
No, I don't recall.
我不..不记得了
Gordon, you want me?
戈登 你找我吗?
Oh, yeah, morphine.
关于吗啡
3rd Platoon ponied up the contraband.
第三排把它用光了
You still looking for scissors?
你还在找剪刀吗?
Yes, I am.
对
Perconte.
找派康提
Perconte?
派康提
Doc.
医生
Thank you.
谢谢你
And you'd better check on Joe Toye out on the OP.
你最好去观测所找乔托伊
He's missing something.
他缺了些东西
Thanks.
谢谢
You guys okay?
你们还好吗?
They got hot food. Can you smell it?
他们有热餐吃 闻到了吗?
- Toye, are you missing something? - Home.
- 托伊 你想要什么吗? - 回家
Ask him to dance, Doc.
医生 叫他跳个舞
Toye, show me your feet.
托伊 你的脚给我看
You watch the goddamn line, McClung.
你给我看好前线 麦克朗
- Where are your boots? - In Washington, up General Taylor's ass.
- 你的靴子呢? - 在华盛顿 泰勒将军的屁股上
- I don't believe this. - I can move better in bare feet, Doc.
- 我才不相信 - 我光脚比较好走 医生
What happened?
发生什么事?
I took them off to dry my goddamn socks.
我把靴子脱了想弄干袜子
They got blown to hell, okay?
结果被炸飞了
What's your size?
你穿几号?
Nine, just like everybody else.
9号 跟大家一样
Frank, you keep cleaning those teeth, the Germans will see you a mile away.
法兰克! 你再刷牙 德军一里外就能看到你
- Shoot you dead. - That's right, Pee Wee, you keep laughing.
- 一枪毙了你! - 没错 小不点 你尽管笑吧
Hey, Doc.
医生
My stuff!
我的东西
Come on, Doc. You got a drug store in here?
拜托 医生 你在开药店啊?
No, I own my stuff.
哪有 这都是我自己的
What are you looking for?
你在找什么?
Scissors. Thank you, Perconte.
剪刀 谢谢你 派康提
My goddamn scissors!
我的剪刀
- Sergeant Guarnere. - Gene, is that you?
- 葛奈瑞中士 - 马林 是你吗?
Hey, Doc! Doc, come here!
医生! 过来这里
USO. Picking up Syrettes. Alley, Liebgott, you got any?
劳军团来搜集止痛针 艾力、李高特 你们有吗?
No, got used in Holland, Doc.
没有 在荷兰用掉了
You ain't using this stuff, are you, Doc, personally?
你没在用这玩意吧 医生? 我是说私人用途?
Come on.
得了
Hey, Doc, I still got the itching.
医生 我还是会痒
Every time I pee, it's murder.
每次尿尿都痛的要死
I'm sorry, but I don't have penicillin for your...
我知道 很抱歉 我就是没有盘尼西林来治你兄弟
My what?
我的什么?
Make sure you move around. Get your blood flowing.
中尉! 你要走动让血液流动
I can't feel my feet.
我的脚麻了
That's why you gotta move, so you don't get trench foot.
对 所以你得走动一下 这样才不会得战壕脚
Should I take my boots off?
我要把靴子脱掉吗?
All you gotta do is just loosen them up, keep moving.
不用 只要松开走一走
Sergeant, I'm sorry.
抱歉 中士
Look, I know it must be hell, but I can't help you, all right?
我知道你很难受 可是我爱莫能助
Just drink lots of water.
你多喝水就是了
Water? It's pissing that hurts!
水? 我就是小便会痛啊!
Shut it! Shut the hell up!
安静!给我闭嘴!
What's going on here, Bill? Who the hell's singing?
这里是怎么回事 比尔? 是谁在唱歌?
I'll find out, Lieutenant. I'll find out, I'll shut them up.
我会查出来的 中尉 我会找出来 叫他们闭嘴
"Lord, grant that I shall never seek So much to be consoled as to console
主啊 答应我今后无需再如此迫切寻求慰籍 与安慰别人
"To be understood, as to understand Or to be loved
被了解 去了解别人 被爱
"As to love with all my heart.
及全心爱人
"With all my heart"
用我全心去爱
Medic!
医护兵!
- Perconte, you getting a jeep? - I'm on it, Doc.
- 派康提 叫吉普车来! - 快啊 医生
- Look what they did to my leg! - Easy CP!
- 看他们怎么对待我的腿! - Ｅ连指挥部
Easy CP, this is Perconte. Sisk has been hit and I need a jeep.
Ｅ连指挥部 我是派康提! 西斯克中弹 我需要辆吉普
I say it again, I need a jeep now!
再说一遍 我现在需要辆吉普车
They're moving, goddamn it! We need it now!
他们在移动了 可恶 我们现在就要
Okay, Sisk, it ain't that bad.
好了 西斯克 没有那么糟
Ain't that bad?
没有那么糟?
Pull!
拉!
No, Doc, save the morphine, I can make it. I can make it, save it, okay?
不要 医生 留着吗啡 我撑得过来 我撑得过来 留着 好吗?
All right, let's get him out of here.
好吧 我们带他离开这里
- Where's the goddamn jeep? - I don't know, but I hear it.
- 死吉普车在哪? - 我不知道 可我听到声音了
Jesus Christ!
我的老天!
You got blood all over my trousers.
史基尼 你的血沾的我满裤子都是
I'm real sorry, Frank!
我真的很抱歉 法兰克
Get him up.
把他扶起来
Damn it, Skinny.
该死的
Tell Spina I went in for plasma.
告诉史宾纳我去找血浆
Come on.
来吧
All the tanks, artillery, are pulled back to here.
所有的坦克 炮兵都撤到这里来
We've got no backup beyond Bastogne. This is it.
我们在巴斯通之外没有后援 就是这样了
The Krauts captured the 326th Medical, and they took everybody...
德军俘虏了第326医疗营 带走了所有的人
...doctors, medics, the whole shebang.
医生 医务兵 整个营
We got nothing.
我们什么也不剩
They're giving the boys hooch for the pain.
他们给弟兄们烈酒来止痛
He took a mortar hit. Watch the leg.
他被迫击炮击中 注意他的腿
- Yeah, watch the leg. - Get him in.
- 对 小心我的腿 - 抬他进去
- Move it! - Coming through.
- 让开! - 借过!
'Morning, fellas.
早 小伙子们
No, no, here, put him here.
把他放到这里
Yes, ma'am.
是的 女士
Is he bad?
他严重吗?
No, lower-leg wound, no morphine.
不 小腿受伤 没打吗啡
Nurse, have you got plasma? I can...
护士! 你有没有血浆可以让我...
Wait, please.
请你等一下
What's going on here? Why aren't these men evacuated?
这里是怎么回事? 为什么这些人没有疏散?
We can't evacuate. We're cut off.
我们没法疏散 后路被切断了
This is as far as it goes.
这是能撤得最远的地方了
Faites attention aux deplacements.
注意血浆(法语)
Ca va?
你好吗? (法语)
Ce n'est pas grave, ce n'est pas urgent.
这不是最紧急的(法语)
I'm in heaven, Doc.
医生 我现在在天堂
Pas encore, Dieu merci.
还没有 谢谢你(法语)
Nurse?
护士?
This way.
这边请
I need morphine, I need bandages, whatever you've got.
我需要吗啡和绷带 你有什么都给我
Okay, I can give you a little, but not a lot.
我可以给你分一些 但是不能太多
There you go. You can have this today.
拿去吧 这个你拿走
Do you want that?
你要那个吗?
Wait. You got plasma?
要 你有血浆吗?
A little.
一点点
Are you a surgeon?
你是外科大夫吗?
No, we don't got no surgeon.
不是 我们没有外科大夫
What's this?
这是什么?
From the bed.
从床上扯下来的
- What, sheets? - Yes, for bandages.
- 床单吗? - 对 当绷带用的
Yeah
好
- Voila. - Merci.
- 都在这儿了 - 谢谢(法语)
Comment vous appelez-vous?
你叫什么名字? (法语)
My name is Renee.
我叫芮妮
I'm Gene, Eugene Roe.
我叫尤金 尤金罗
Where are you from?
你是哪里人?
Louisiana, half-Cajun.
路易斯安那 1/4印第安血统
Et toi, d'ou viens-tu?
你呢? 你是哪里人? (法语)
Bastogne.
巴斯通
Can you get me back to the line?
你可以载我回前线吗?
Sure.
当然
Eugene.
尤金
Chocolat.
巧克力(法语)
Pour vous.
给你的(法语)
Benedictio dei omnipotentis patri et filii...
(拉丁祷文)
Amen. Amen.
阿门! 阿门!
Fight well for your God and your country.
好好为你的主及国家作战
God bless you all, and stay safe.
上帝祝福你们 一切小心
That's it, guys, nothing more to worry about.
就这样了 各位 没什么好再担心的
We're gonna die now, we're gonna die in a state of grace.
我们就是要死了 也要在祥和的状态下死去
Isn't that right, Babe?
是不是这样 贝比?
Battalion want a reconnaissance patrol.
营部要派一个侦察任务
Kraut hunting.
寻找德军
All right, I'll go. Take these.
好 我去 拿着这些
Give the boots to Joe Toye. Tell him they're a nine.
把靴子给乔托伊 告诉他这是9号的
Keep going, till we make some kind of contact.
一直走 直到我们与敌方遭遇为止
- Peacock's leading, right? - Right.
- 皮卡克带队 是不是? - 是的
Asshole couldn't find a snowball in a blizzard.
这笨蛋啥都找不到
That's what's happening, that's the order.
情况就是这样 这是命令
- Sarge? - Yeah, Julian.
- 中士! - 什么事 朱利安
Let me be the lead scout.
让我当尖兵
Back of the line, Private.
归队 二等兵
- All right, that's it, let's move out. - Tactical columns, gentlemen.
- 好 就这样 我们出发了! - 成战术纵队 各位
Doc, it's a combat patrol.
医生 医生 这是战斗巡逻
Why don't you stay back and keep your ass out of trouble?
你何不退后免得惹祸 好吗?
Yes, sir. Yeah.
好的 中士
Come on, Hoobler, pick it up.
快点 胡伯勒 赶上来
Right, move on.
前进
Go.
走
- Fire! - Get down! Get down!
- 开火!(德语) - 快趴下!
Jesus!
老天
Shit!
可恶!
Bull! Christenson!
大牛! 克里斯登生!
Up on line!
到战线上!
Johnny!
强尼!
We got a man down!
我们有人中弹了
Jack, over here.
杰克?
What have we got?
情况如何?
- Keep still, Julian! - We've gotta make a move!
- 不要动 朱利安! - 我们得离开这里!
I can get him, Sarge.
我可以去救他 中士
Suppressing fire!
压制火力!
One man down, Easy!
Ｅ连指挥所 有人中弹倒地!
Okay, stay there, don't move!
待在那里不要动
Stop moving, or else they'll keep shooting!
不然他们会开枪打你
What's happening, sir?
发生什么事 长官?
We're pulling back.
我们要撤退了
We made contact. I gotta get to the CP.
我们遭遇德军 我得回到指挥部
Don't move! Stop moving! They'll keep firing! Stop moving!
别动! 他们会继续射击的 不要动! 不要动!
Jesus Christ, fuck it!
可恶
- John! - What?
- 约翰 - 什么?
Pull back, we gotta pull back!
撤退 我们得撤退了!
- Let's get the hell out of here! - Let's go, let's go!
- 我们快走吧! - 我们走!
Move! Go!
走了!
Stay with us, stay with us!
你要撑着!
Hold on, Julian! Stay with us! Look at me, stay with us!
撑着 朱利安!看着我 撑下去!
Look at me, hold on, hold on!
撑着!
Don't move, Julian, we're coming back!
别动 朱利安 我们会回来的!
We'll get you out of here, just hold on!
我们会救你回去的 撑下去!
Go! Let's go!
走 我们走!
Move!
快走!
- Come on, let's go! - Where the hell are we?
- 快点 我们走! - 我们到底在哪儿?
Straight ahead, straight ahead!
往前直走! 往前直走!
Doc!
医生!
Okay, Christenson set it up on the rock.
克里斯登生 把它架在石头上
Easy CP, Easy CP, lightning. Over.
Ｅ连指挥所 这是闪电
I need an A-jeep standing by at the CP.
我需要吉普车在指挥所待命
Okay, got you a jeep, Doc.
好了 帮你弄到吉普车了 医生
Martin!
马丁!
- Sir! - What's going on?
- 长官! - 发生什么事?
They got Julian!
他们打中朱利安!
- He's still alive! - We don't know that!
- 他还活着! - 我们并不确定!
- We gotta go get him! - Did you hit an OP or their line?
- 得去救他 长官! - 遭遇的是敌军观测所还是锋线?
Their line, sir!
是锋线 长官!
We've gotta go back, get Julian out of there!
我们得回去把朱利安救出来!
- No, fall back! - We lost Peacock.
- 不 回防! - 我们找不到皮卡克
- No, he's back at the CP. - Come on, Martin, fall back!
- 他回到指挥所了 - 快点 马丁 回防线上!
Get him out of here!
叫他们都离开!
Let's up and go!
我们快走吧!
Doc, we've gotta move now, Doc. Come on, let's go!
医生 我们现在得走了
Doc, now, let's go!
来吧 我们走!
Move!
快走!
- Let's go! - Fall back!
- 我们走! - 退回去!
We couldn't get to him, Captain.
我们救不了他 上尉
We tried. Babe tried. We couldn't get to him.
我们尽力了 贝比也尽力了 就是救不了他
People
大伙儿
Let me sit in here with you guys.
让我跟你们一起坐
Heffron?
赫夫朗?
Toye.
托伊
What you doing out here?
你在这里干什么?
Thanks for the boots, Doc. Doing fine.
谢谢你的靴子 医生 我现在很好
Are you still having trouble with your feet?
你的脚还是有问题吗?
Show me, let me see it.
给我看 让我看看
It's trench foot, Toye.
这是战壕脚 托伊
If it turns gangrene, you could lose it.
如果长了坏疽就要截肢了
I ain't coming off the line, Doc.
医生 我绝不从战线上退下
You gotta stay dry.
你得保持干燥
Massage your feet.
按摩你的脚
Change socks every day and dry the wet ones around your neck.
每天更换袜子 把湿袜子围在脖子弄干
- Trying. - Do it.
- 试试看 - 必须做到
I'm working on it.
我正在努力
- You seen Heffron? - No.
- 你有看到赫夫朗吗? - 没有
Why?
怎么了?
He ain't in his hole.
他不在他的坑里
Fuck.
可恶
Got you.
找到你了
Heffron?
赫夫朗?
Edward?
爱德华
Eat it.
吃吧
Good.
很好
Perfect.
非常好
I promised him, if he got hit...
我答应过他 如果他中弹了...
...I'd get his stuff and bring it to his ma, you know?
我会把他的东西带回去给他妈
Now the fucking Krauts will strip him.
现在那些混帐德国佬会把他给剥光
No, it's okay.
不会有事的
It's not! It's not okay.
怎么会! 一定有事的
I should've got to him.
应该回去救他的
What do you call those people again? Those Cajun healers?
你怎么称呼那些...半印第安血统的医疗师?
Traiteurs.
巫医
You know, my grandma was a traiteur.
我的祖母就是位巫医
Your grandmother? No shit?
你祖母? 没开玩笑?
She was.
是的
Laid her hands on people and cured them.
只要把手放在病人身上就治好他们
Took away sickness, cancer, you name it.
带走疾病...癌症...什么都行
Your grandma did that? You're shitting me.
你祖母真做的到? 别唬我了!
I remember she used to pray a lot.
我记得她常祷告
Yeah, I guess she had to.
是啊 我想她一定得这么做
Talked to God about the pain she pulled out.
告诉上帝她要移除的病痛
Asked him to...
央求神明
...carry it away.
把病痛带走
That's what she did.
她就是这么做的
Jesus.
天啊
I'm still trying to figure why they picked me for a medic.
我还在想为什么他们会挑我当医护兵
God knows.
天晓得
Snap of a finger, and just like that, you're a medic.
手指一指 就这样成了医护兵
I've had enough playing doctor.
我已经受够扮医生了
How about you?
你呢?
Joe.
乔
Take cover
找掩护
Cease fire!
停止射击!
Cease fire, goddamn it!
停止射击 可恶!
Sergeant, I don't understand! It was our own planes!
中士 我不懂 那不是我们的飞机吗?
C-47's.
是Ｃ－47
They're bringing supplies. It's a drop.
他们带来补给了 这是空投
It's a drop, come on!
这是空投 快来!
All right, help the doc.
好了 去帮医生忙
The rest of you come with me.
其他人跟我来
Medic!
医务兵!
Someone give us a hand here!
谁来帮帮我们?
Help, help!
帮个忙!
This one through here.
这个从这边穿过去
Now, vite!
快点!
Fais pression, essaie de trouver I'artere.
(法语)
The artery, gotta find the artery!
我们得找出动脉
Moi, je ne la trouve pas!
我找不到!(法语)
Anna!
安娜!
Where does she come from?
她打哪儿来的?
The black girl?
那个黑人女孩?
The Congo.
刚果
How'd she get here?
她怎么会来到这里?
Just like me.
跟我一样
She came to help.
她来帮忙的
Chocolat?
巧克力? (法语)
What?
怎么了?
Your hands.
你的手
My hands?
我的手?
You're a good nurse.
你是个好护士
No.
我不是
I never want to treat another wounded man again.
我不想再处理伤兵了
I'd rather work in a butcher shop.
我宁愿在肉铺里工作
But your touch...
可是你的触碰
...calms people.
让人镇定
That's a gift from God.
这是上天给的天赋
No, it's not a gift.
不 这不是天赋
God would never give such a painful thing.
上帝不会给人那么痛苦的东西
Nurse!
护士!
We need some help over here!
我们这里需要帮忙!
Guy's shot through the stomach.
有人胃部被打穿了
How bad is it?
有多严重
Okay, get this one in first.
好 先把这人抬进去
You'll be all right.
你会没事的 你会熬过来的
Now we know how they felt.
我现在知道他们的感受了
What? Who?
什么? 谁?
The legionnaires...
高卢外籍军团的战士
...when they were watching the Huns...
当他们看着匈奴人
...the Goths, the Visigoths.
哥德人及西哥特人
Visigoths? Jesus Christ.
西哥特人?
Barbarians.
就是那些野蛮人
They came right through here.
他们以前就从这里经过
Right through these trees, just sweeping down...
就是从这些树丛之间穿过
...to burn the shit out of Rome.
一路扫荡直奔罗马焚城
That's a hell of a long ride.
那路程可真遥远啊!
So what's college like, Buck?
你的大学生活如何 巴克?
You got time to hit the books...
你能有空念书吗? 当...
...with cheerleaders running their fingers through your hair?
啦啦队员拨弄着你的头发
Hell, Babe I can't even remember.
天啊 贝比 我竟然不记得了
Hey, it's Doc.
是医生
- Sergeant. - Heffron.
- 中士! - 赫夫朗
Lieutenant.
中尉
Wrap up.
包扎一下
Never calls anybody by their nickname.
他从不叫大家的绰号
He once called me Edward.
他有次叫我爱德华
Is that right?
真的?
Edward? That's your name?
你的本名叫爱德华?
Yeah.
是
Funny.
好玩
You don't look like an Edward.
你看来不像是个"爱德华"
Hey, Doc.
医生
It's gonna get busy, pal.
看来又有得忙了
Hold your fire, boys. Don't let them draw you out.
不要射击 弟兄们 别上当暴露你们位置
- Hold your fire! - Stay ready, boys.
- 不要射击! - 大家保持待命
What the hell are we gonna hit those things with, Lip?
我们要用什么来打那些玩意 李普?
Hold your fire! Get ready, Walter!
不要射击! 准备好 华特
Stay in your holes, guys.
留在散兵坑里
Smokey's hit! Medic!
史摩基中弹了 医护兵!
Eugene, let's go!
尤金! 我们走!
- Come on, let's go! - Okay.
- 快点 我们走! - 好
Go!
走!
Ready.
准备
Medic!
医护兵!
Doc! Smokey!
医生! 史摩基!
Hi, Mo.
阿摩
I got it, I'm keeping it for you.
我来拿 我会帮你保管
Smoke! I can't feel my legs, Gene.
我的脚没知觉了 尤金
Take it easy. My foxhole, get the plasma, now!
放松 去我的散兵坑拿血浆 快去
Here they come!
他们来了!
- You got them? - I got them. Go!
- 你一人来弄? - 我来弄 快去!
Machine guns, open fire!
机枪群开火!
Open fire!
转换射击阵地!
Sergeant Lipton!
李普军士长!
Doc, we gotta get the hell out of here.
医生 我们得离开这里
Stay with us, Smokey. Stay with us!
撑下去 史摩基! 撑下去!
We gotta get the hell outta here!
我们得快离开!
You ready?
准备好了吗?
All right, go!
好了 走!
- Stop, we've gotta stop. - All right.
- 停 我们得停一下 - 好的
- Take the plasma. - All right.
- 拿着血浆 - 好的
Come on, Walt.
撑着 华特
Come on, buddy.
挺着 兄弟
Hurry, Doc, come on, Doc. I've gotta get back to the line.
快点医生 我得回到战线上
Okay, okay.
好的 好的
- Lip? - Yeah, buddy.
- 李普? - 我在听
You're standing on my hand.
你踩到我的手了
Sorry.
对不起 兄弟
Look, I'll get you another Purple Heart for it.
听好 我会再颁个紫心勋章给你
Give us a hand!
帮我们个忙
I got you a ride, Doc.
我帮你弄到车了 医生
Jones!
琼斯!
Give it here.
放在这儿
Okay, put him here.
好了 把他放在这里
Where's his tag?
他的兵籍牌呢?
Where's his tag? What's wrong with him?
他的兵籍牌呢? 他是怎么了?
Paralyzed.
瘫痪了
What?
什么?
He's paralyzed.
他瘫痪了
Can't feel a thing.
没有任何感觉
"In the name of the Father of the Son and of the Holy Spirit
以圣父圣子圣灵之名
"Amen"
阿门
Eugene?
尤金?
- Are you... - Renee, I need some help here.
- 你要... - 芮妮 这里需要帮忙
Are you all right?
你还好吗?
Renee!
芮妮
Here you go, man.
这个给你
- One for the doc? - Sure.
- 一份给医生 - 好的
Doc?
医生?
Better than sitting down to a Christmas Eve dinner of turkey and hooch back at the division CP.
这总比坐在师指挥所吃圣诞火鸡餐和烈酒好
Damned if I don't like old Joe Domingus' rancid-ass beans better.
我就是爱吃野战口粮与臭豆子罐头
- Hello, Easy Company. - Hello, sir.
- Ｅ连将士们好啊! - 长官好!
Hello, sir.
长官好
General McAuliffe sent a message to the entire division.
麦考利夫将军发布了一个消息给整个师
I thought maybe your people would like to hear it.
我想你应该让大家知道
That should be your prerogative, sir.
长官 这是你的特权
All right.
好
Men!
兄弟们!
General McAuliffe wishes us all a Merry Christmas.
麦考利夫将军祝我们大家圣诞节愉快
"What's merry about all this, you ask.
你们会问这有什么值得快乐的?
"Just this.
就是这些
"We've stopped cold everything that's been thrown at us from the north, east, south and west.
我们已经阻止了来自东西南北四方来的攻势
"Now, two days ago the German commander demanded our honorable surrender...
两天前德军指挥官 要求我们光荣投降...
"...to save the USA encircled troops from total annihilation.
以免被包围的美军遭到全部歼灭
"The German commander received the following reply:
德军指挥官收到如下的回复
"'To the German commander:
给德军指挥官
"'Nuts! '
神经病!
"We're giving our country and our loved ones at home a worthy Christmas present.
我们给了国家以及在家乡所爱的人 一个有价值的圣诞礼物
"And being privileged to take part in this gallant feat of arms...
我们有幸参与这场英勇的圣战
"...we're truly making for ourselves a merry Christmas."
我们真正为自己创造了...快乐圣诞!
Merry Christmas to you all, and God bless you.
祝大家圣诞快乐 上帝保佑你们
Merry Christmas, sir.
圣诞快乐 长官
Nuts!
神经病!
Bill.
比尔
Picture of my girl.
我女友照片
Good looking broad, Buck.
很漂亮的小妞 巴克
She's...
她...
She's finished with me.
她已经跟我分手了
Yeah?
是吗?
Yeah.
对
Yeah, she's...
对啊 她是...
Just in time for Christmas.
刚好赶上圣诞节 对吧?
Shit! I almost forgot.
可恶! 我差点忘了!
- Lucky Strikes means fine tobacco. - Where the hell did you get those?
- 好彩牌香烟才是好料 - 你打哪儿弄来的?
Merry Christmas, fellas.
大家圣诞快乐!
Gotta thank jolly old Saint Luz.
该谢谢快乐的老圣人鲁兹
Beautiful.
棒呆了
There you go, Penk.
拿去吧 潘卡拉
I am shaking so goddamn much I feel like I'm dancing.
我抖的太厉害 感觉好像在跳舞
There you go, buddy. There you go.
拿去抽吧!
Frank, what are you doing?
法兰克! 你在干什么?
It's Christmas, Pee Wee.
今天是圣诞节 小不点
Here, Frank.
拿去 法兰克
- What is it? - Lemon-powder snow cone.
- 这是什么? - 柠檬口味刨冰
Pass. Merry fucking Christmas.
免了! 去他的圣诞快乐
Harry.
哈利
- Fire's not a good idea. - Just a couple of minutes.
- 生火可不是好主意 - 几分钟就好
We're in a dell.
我们在林中谷地
A dell?
林中谷地?
Like where fairies and gnomes live?
仙子和矮人住的地方?
I swear I thought I could smell a fire.
我发誓闻到升火的味道
I did smell a fire.
我是闻到升火
Are you out of your mind?
你们疯了吗?
We're in a dell.
我们位于林中谷地
Down! Crossfire!
卧倒!
God, no!
上帝啊 不!
This is Captain Nixon. I need an A-jeep for Second Battalion CP.
这是尼克森上尉 第二营指挥部需要一辆吉普车
- Stay still, Harry. - Doc, put that out!
- 哈利 不要动 - 医生 把火弄熄!
Repeat, A-jeep for Second Battalion CP.
重复 第二营指挥部需要一辆吉普车
Medic!
医护兵!
Doc!
医生!
Come on, Doc.
快点 医生
- Is he hurt? - I don't know.
- 他受伤了吗? - 不知道
Move, get in!
隐蔽!
Doc!
医生!
I gotta go.
我得走了
Eugene, come on, get up. The captain's yelling.
尤金 快点 起来 上尉在喊了
- Come on, get up. - Okay.
- 快点站起来 - 好
Okay, get up! Not lie down!
好 快起来 不是躺下
Okay, get up, come on, move! Jesus Christ!
快点起来了! 快点! 我的天!
My hand, my goddamned hand!
我的手 可恶!
Roe!
罗!
Jesus!
老天!
Okay.
还好吗?
Roe?
罗?
Stay still, Harry.
躺着别动 哈利
Just a scratch. You're not getting out this easy.
这只是擦伤 没那么简单就可以离开战场
Jeep's on it's way. Hang tough. Here's a towel.
吉普车在路上了 忍着点 这里有毛巾
Towel.
毛巾
Yeah sure.
好的
I got morphine in my pocket. Give it to him.
我袋子里有吗啡 给他用
- Where you want it? - Opposite thigh.
- 你要打在哪儿? - 另一侧大腿
Okay.
好了
Elevate his head.
抬高他的头
Get him up.
把他抬起来
There you go, soldier, take that.
这个给你 阿兵哥 拿着
Eugene, get yourself into town, get a hot meal.
进城去弄个热餐吃
Get out, quick!
让开!
Clear the road!
快让路!
Stay out of there!
快离开那里
Keep moving!
继续前进!
Medic!
医护兵!
Get your ass out here!
赶快出来帮忙!
Come on!
快点!
Every hour, on the hour, on the radio, but I don't know where the hell you are.
每个整点都用无线电找你 我根本不知你在哪
Everything okay?
一切还好吗?
Babe?
贝比?
Yeah.
很好
How'd you do that?
你是怎么弄的?
You did that.
是你弄的
I'll fix it up.
我来帮你包扎
Hey, Gene. You called me Babe.
尤金 你刚叫我贝比
I did?
我有吗?
When?
什么时候?
Just now.
就是刚才
Babe.
贝比
I guess I did.
我想我是这么叫你的
Heffron, watch the goddamn line.
赫夫朗 你看好前线